DONNA THOMPSON

704-909-9596 DonnaThompson325@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Experienced Information Technology (IT) professional with a diverse background as a software engineer, application developer, data analyst, business analyst (BA), production support and software trainer in the financial sector, as well as in telecommunications, healthcare, and education spaces. Extensive technical knowledge and excellent interpersonal skills enable me to collaborate well with all levels of an organization. My passion for continual learning and a natural growth mindset drive business value for my team.

SKILLS

- 11+ years as a software engineer/application developer & 10+ years as a technical business analyst, with extensive experience in all phases of the SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle) in the financial and banking industry, telecommunications, healthcare, and education spaces
- Adept at analyzing business requirements and building business solutions at enterprise scale, designing and coding apps, UI/GUI design, ETL (Extract, Transform, Load), testing, deployment, change management & production support.
- Experienced in software engineering in both Agile (3+ years) & Waterfall (8+years)
 methodologies with SQL (11 years) and COBOL II (8 years) in Oracle SQL Developer/
 PL/SQL, Microsoft SQL Server/T-SQL, and DB2 databases.
- Experience with Jira, Confluence, and ALM work management tools, for Agile software development in both Scrum and Kanban methodologies.
- Experienced in change management in PAC2000, ensuring data integrity pre- & postrelease of changes to critical IT systems and services.
- Performs & documents in-depth data analysis of production and test data, to mitigate risk and improve business solutions.
- Ability to present complex information in an understandable manner to all key stakeholders.
- Excellent relationship manager, collaborating and building trust in cross-functional teams of product owners, application developers, operations, internal business partners, project management, and senior management.
- Excels as a liaison with users to provide software training and demos, resolve issues, assess business needs, and recommend changes to achieve optimum user experience
- Experienced in developing documentation artifacts with dev team, end users, PMO and stakeholders, for Business Requirements Document (BRD), Product Requirements (PRD), Functional Specs (FSD), Traceability Matrix and Scope of Work (SOW) documents
- Conducts retrospective of issue resolution and identifies opportunities for improvement
- Clear, accurate & thorough verbal, written, and interpersonal communication skills
- Takes ownership to balance and prioritize multiple fast-paced complex projects; dynamically shifts focus to the highest priorities and effectively delivers desired outcomes
- Creative, innovative, and strategic thinker; works well with a team and independently
- Analytical, quantitative, and technical problem-solving skills with intuitive research skills

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCIES

T-SQL, PL/SQL, ANSI SQL, Oracle SQL Developer, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), Data Analysis Reconciliation Tool (DART), Intellimatch, Snapshot,

RIE, PAC2000, Jira (Scrum, Kanban), Confluence, HP ALM, SharePoint, Windows PowerShell, JCL, DB2, MVS/XA, Unix, XML, Forté OOL, CICS, Visio, Access, COBOL II

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wells Fargo - Charlotte, NC Software Engineer, Jan 2020 - present

- Software Engineer and SQL Developer in the Financial and Banking industry in Wholesale Technology LOB supporting Capital Markets, Wells Fargo Securities.
- Agile software development, using the Kanban and Scrum frameworks in Jira and Confluence software.
- Develop reconciliation applications in the internal DART framework (Data Analysis Reconciliation Tool) using SQL (T-SQL, PL/SQL).
- Analyzed business requirements and building business solutions at enterprise scale; designed and coded recons; performed ETL (Extract, Transform, Load), UI/GUI design, testing, production deployment, production support & change management.
- Collaborate with stakeholders to capture and analyze business requirements.
- Design DART software solutions in DART based on business requirements, providing demos
 to business partners and adapting solutions to reflect business feedback.
- Code DART recons, with data sources from Oracle SQL Developer and Microsoft SQL Server databases, and Broadridge, SWIFT, and other financial file formats.
- Perform functional, unit, and regression testing in lower test environments (UAT, SIT) until business goals are achieved and user signoff is complete.
- Promote DART & Intellimatch software solutions to Production in change management events, preparing CR documentation for executive signoff, & validating DBA's work.
- Modify existing DART recons to add functionality, per business requirements.
- Perform & document in-depth data analysis and implement business requirements for the FIS Intellimatch tool, a third-party Bank Reconciliation System, in databases on 6 servers.
- Create extracts from upstream input files and ORACLE databases, to feed into Intellimatch
- Modify existing Intellimatch extracts for updated input file formats and new data sources.
- Convert multiple existing SSIS jobs to DART recons and import into Intellimatch.
- Implement change management in PAC2000, ensuring data integrity pre- & post-release of changes to critical IT systems and services.
- Documented workflow in Confluence and later in Jira on Kanban board, pulling work from backlog as prioritized by Business.
- GPTM (Global Post-Trade Management) project design, code and test DART recons and Intellimatch feeds for a new data source being implemented by Broadridge Financial Services, a global Fintech company.
- Perform 5 rounds of GPTM project mock testing for Intellimatch and DART, in collaboration with Broadridge and ISP upstream partners and Wells Fargo Securities middle office team.
- Contribute to and ensure accuracy in GPTM project artifacts, including FSD, traceability matrix, Success criteria, Test Case Scenarios
- Conduct GPTM testing preparations: Identifying impacted Intellimatch and DART tables and files, create and run queries on database and analyze results.
- Stage data for GPTM mock testing, set up prior day balances in Intellimatch database, ensure lookup tables and files match PROD. Deport mock data if needed, after testing.
- Design and create a Test Plan and Test Cases in HP ALM tool (Application Lifeycle Management) for each round of mock testing and for the go-live event.
- Execute Test Cases for each round of testing: Run DART recons and validate output, perform detailed analysis on all input files, import extract files into Intellimatch, run queries on inscope ORACLE tables, analyze results of imports and queries, as compared to PROD.
- Identify defects and issues from testing, using analysis of import results, NDM logs, and backend queries. Present detailed examples to upstream partners ISP and Broadridge.

- Resolved issues and defects in working sessions with Wells Fargo Securities business partners, upstream teams Broadridge and ISP, and PMO team.
- Effectively manages competing priorities to ensure successful completion of tasks
- Create accounts/balance pools/currencies in Intellimatch for new GPTM company in lower environments (DEV, UAT, and SIT), after each database refresh.
- Attend multiple daily GPTM meetings and working sessions (hosted in Cisco WebEx, Zoom, Teams, or Skype) to ensure milestones are met.
- Update Intellimatch user 'edit privileges' in lower environments with recent changes after database refresh, and perform detailed analysis for all 6 servers, as compared to PROD.
- Schedule software jobs via RIE Dashboard tool, using Cron expressions or trigger files.

EX-Factory - Charlotte, NC Business Analyst, Oct 2019 – Jan 2020

- Performing data archiving on CRM database in a distribution environment
- · Tuning database performance by consolidating and streamlining searchable keys
- Providing data mining and analysis to clean up legacy CRM application data

Independent consultant - Decatur, IN Business Analyst, 2017 - 2019

- Implemented multiple COTS software systems, maintained database (MS Access)
- Executed network upgrades and hardware refresh projects
- Completed training in JavaScript, ANSI SQL, MS SQL Server, Project Management Best Practices, PAC2000, Visual Basic for Applications (VBA), Jira, Confluence, Gantt Charts, SharePoint, Agile for developers/testers, Agile for business analysts, XML, Extract Transform & Load (ETL), Visio, Scrum, Kanban, and .Net Framework

North Adams Community Schools - Decatur, IN Senior Office Administrator / Business Analyst, 2014 – 2016

- Provided detailed data analysis and design of multiple projects, gathering and documenting business requirements (BRD) and scope of work (SOW) in the education sector
- Performed risk mitigation, project execution, and process documentation, leading to improved business processes, staying in compliance with Federal regulations regarding student data
- Managed rapidly changing priorities, ensuring project completion on time and under budget

First Response, Inc. - Decatur, IN

Business Analyst, 2012 - 2014

- Business systems administrator for site-wide retail and finance software & hardware systems
- Performed data mining and data analysis to improve business processes
- Worked with financial institutions to manage corporate budgets, payroll, taxes, EOM, EOY
- Database maintenance of customer transaction database

EMS Source, Inc. - Greensboro, NC Business Analyst, 2008 – 2012

- Wrote complex SQL queries with JOINs on multiple tables, and analyzed data to improve business processes in insurance / healthcare industry, assuring compliance with Federal HIPAA, Medicaid and Medicare regulations.
- In an Agile environment, collaborated with client senior management to capture requirements for financial billing application; developed test cases; performed functional testing
- Performed data modeling & created Access database for mission-critical customer data
- Implemented document database, converting 50,000+ documents, reducing expenses
- Provided on-site technical software training to end users

Massage Envy - Greensboro, NC Business Analyst, 2007 – 2008

- Performed data analysis and risk mitigation to improve monthly and quarterly accounting processes in support of financial department; Excel reports (VBA/macros/pivot tables)
- Managed corporate data feeds with financial institutions, ensuring data integrity

Flower Tributes, Inc. - Greensboro, NC Business Analyst, 2003 – 2007

- Oversaw SDLC from inception phase to implementation and collaborated with all stakeholders, including SME, end users, business lines and senior management
- Led the requirement design process and documented complex information in an understandable manner in the Business Requirements Document (BRD), Product Requirements (PRD) and Functional Specs (FSD)
- Configured & implemented new COTS software installation

Computing Solutions and Services - Hickory, NC Technical Analyst, 1997 – 2003

- Implemented multiple COTS software systems and maintained database (MS Access)
- Provided users with proactive guidance & training to achieve optimum customer experience
- Managed issue backlog and used data analysis to identify opportunities for improvement
- Executed network upgrades and hardware refresh projects

ALCATEL - Claremont, NC Software Engineer / Application Developer, 1996 – 1997

- Waterfall application development / SDLC in COBOL II in telecommunications industry
- Data analysis and technical documentation for in-house AR/AP application
- Trained in ORACLE; Wrote complex SQL queries with JOINs on multiple tables
- Led JAD sessions with cross-functional teams and key stakeholders, software developers, and end users to gather complex business and functional requirements

NORTEL - Morrisville, NC Software Engineer / Application Developer, 1989 – 1996

- Waterfall application development & software engineering in all stages of the SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle), in SQL & COBOL II with CICS in MVS/XA mainframe environment in the telecommunications industry, for in-house training and reporting app. Trained in Objectoriented programming (OOP) in Forté TOOL in Unix.
- Analyzed business requirements & built solutions at enterprise scale; designed and coded apps and DB2 database schemas; performed data analysis, ETL (Extract, Transform, Load), UI/GUI design, testing, production deployment, change management & production support.
- Wrote JCL batch jobs & complex ANSI SQL queries with JOINs to UPDATE, INSERT & DELETE production data; provided 24/7 on-call application support & issue management
- Implemented change management, minimizing disruptions and ensuring data integrity pre- & post-release of changes to critical IT systems and services.
- Developed test plans & cases; performed unit testing, regression testing & integration testing
- Provided on-site software training to business partners/engineers across the Southeast
- Facilitated retrospective meetings, presenting resolution & improvement recommendations
- Led JAD sessions with users; implemented Change Requests (CR); assisted with UAT (user acceptance testing); and ensured end user satisfaction

EDUCATION

Associate of Applied Science – Business Computer Programming

Durham Technical Community College - Durham, NC Cum Laude Honors, 3.88 GPA